GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT Summary

Software Engineer with 3 years of working experience with strengths in developing web based applications using Java & J2EE technologies. \hat{A} Solid understanding of Amazon Web services. Expertise using frameworks Spring and hibernate. Strong knowledge of Restful and Soap web services. Experience in UI technologies angular JS, bootstrap, HTML. \hat{A} Working knowledge on databases Oracle and PostgreSQL Experience with agile development methodologies. \hat{A} \hat{A}

Technical Skills

• Programming Languages : Java, Python,C#,C++

• Databases : Oracle 11g, PostgreSQL, MySql 5.5

• Web Technology: Angular JS, Bootstrap, HTML, CSSÂ Â

• Amazon Web Services : EC2, S3, Lambda, RDS, IAM, ELB, Route53

• Web Services : SOAP, REST

• Web Servers : Apache Tomcat, JBoss

• Frameworks: Spring, Hibernate, JUnit, ASP.Net

• IDE & Reporting tools : Eclipse, Jenkins, Informatica, Jira

• Version Control Tools : GIT

• Operating Systems : DBN, Ubuntu(Linux), Windows

Experience

Graduate Research Assistant 01/2017 to Current University Of San Francisco Sacramento, CA

- Implemented back-end software using A Java A based Lambda functions and Angular JS based front-end.
- Created modules with J2EE using Spring MVC.
- Refactored nested conditions using guard clauses.
- Designed and developed data access layers using Hibernate.
- Using Git as a version control and automating it with Jenkins for execution.
- Used Junit to develop unit test cases.
- Finely tuned the analytical skills and the ability to work in pressure.

Java Developer 06/2015 to 08/2016 Albertsons Company Inc. North Pole, AK

- Involved in Agile software development life cycle which involves designing, coding, testing and debugging.
- Developed and enhanced middle ware components using Collections, Object Serialisation, multi threading and design patterns.
- Created dumps for memory leak and performance improvement and analysed them
- Used Spring MVC framework and integrated with hibernate.
- Developed SOAP and Restful web services for transmission of large blocks of data. A
- Self-learner with passion to learn new technologies and aptitude to pick them quickly.Â
- Easily collaborate with team members and project managers to accomplish the milestones

Intern 11/2014 to 05/2015 Stantec Inc. Indianapolis, IN

- Managed multiple, concurrent processes where necessary, strategically prioritise to ensure all deadlines are met.
- Played a major role in developing the web application using C#, ASP.Net, HTML, Bootstrap and JavaScript.
- Identified business requirements, evaluated proposals and ensured all modifications are addressed to support new and existing business.

Education

Master of Science: Computer Science 2018 University of North Texas, GPA - 3.8 State, United states

 $Bachelor\ of\ Engineering: Information\ Technology\ 2015\ Chaitanya\ Bharathi\ Institute\ of\ Technology\ ,\ GPA-\ 3.6\ City\ ,\ Indianoval and the property of\ Chaitanya\ Bharathi\ Institute\ of\ Technology\ ,\ GPA-\ 3.6\ City\ ,\ Indianoval and\ City\ ,\ Indianoval and\ City\ ,\ Construction\ description\ descri$

Academic projects

Text-voice conversion: Developed a web application to convert the text to voice using java and AWS. The application stored in S3Â triggers the lambda using API to get the text from DB and converts the text to voice and stores it to dynamoDB and S3 which can then be accessed by the user.

Online Blood Donation Management system: Developed, coded, installed, tested, debugged and documented an e-information web application that acts as a gateway between a donor and acceptor of blood where the admin is the central authority of all the activities in the website. (JAVA, MYSQL, JUnit, Selenium, Html, Bootstrap, angular JS)

Inner threats Identification: \hat{A} Identify the inner threat in an organisation by \hat{A} the data captured from CPT tests using Python and Weka. Extracted the behavioural features by collecting the raw data from mouse and key board movements of individuals. Performed data analysis on the features to differentiate the malicious people and achieved an accuracy of 92%. \hat{A}

Attendance Management System: A web application developed for daily student attendance in colleges using java html, bootstrap and javascript. It facilitates to access the attendance information of a student in a particular class which is stored in MySql database by the teacher who sorts and enters data herself according to the attendance obtained in her class.Â

Preserving Location Privacy in Geo Locations: Implemented a new algorithm LocX, a novel alternative that provides significantly-improved location privacy without adding uncertainty into query results or relying on strong assumptions about server security using java and jdbc to connect to mysql database.

Airline Sentimental Analysis: \hat{A} Sentiment classification strategy was applied on Twitter airline data to analyse the data using a $na\tilde{A}$ ve based approach on python and compare the results \hat{A} with \hat{A} WEKA. Activities and Honors

- Chief Coordinator for our departmental Technical fest, a National Level Technical Symposium TECSTASY 2k13.
- Member of Toastmasters club.
- Member of Chaitanya Bharathi Cultural Club